<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>0xChris</title>
    <link>https://www.0xChris.dev/</link>
    <description>0xChris updates</description>
    <atom:link href="https://www.0xChris.dev/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item>
      <title>Tracing The Tracer: Chasing A Funny Bpftrace Bug</title>
      <link>https://www.0xChris.dev/posts/2025-12-29-tracing-the-tracer-chasing-a-funny-bpftrace-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.0xChris.dev/posts/2025-12-29-tracing-the-tracer-chasing-a-funny-bpftrace-bug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently encountered a strange issue with bpftrace while tracing a problem on a real-life Exadata system. The issue was quite intriguing and caused by a combination of the following two factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bpftrace version 0.16.0-6 (shipped with OEL 8.10)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exadata X10 with Capacity on Demand enabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A systematic analysis of the issue required the use of gdb and low-level tracing tools, and ultimately led me to hacking the bpftrace binary. If you enjoy low-level tracing, debugging, dissecting system calls, and diving into Linux kernel source code, this write-up may be of interest to you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Obtain The Source Code For Particular UEK Kernel Versions</title>
      <link>https://www.0xChris.dev/posts/2025-12-28-obtain-the-source-code-for-particular-uek-kernel-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.0xChris.dev/posts/2025-12-28-obtain-the-source-code-for-particular-uek-kernel-versions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the nice aspects of Linux is that its source code is openly available. This also applies to Oracle Linux, which ships with its own Unbreakable Enterprise Kernel (UEK).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UEK kernel sources are publicly available on GitHub and can be obtained via &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;. This short note provides a quick walkthrough on how to obtain and check out the source code for a particular version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-clone-the-uek-github-repository&#34;&gt;Step 1: Clone the UEK GitHub repository&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are behind a proxy, you may need to configure your proxy settings before starting. Then change to a directory with a few GB of free space and clone the repository using &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;. This may take a while, depending on the speed of your connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Printing Non-Null-Terminated Strings With GDB</title>
      <link>https://www.0xChris.dev/posts/2025-12-23-printing-non-null-terminated-strings-with-gdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.0xChris.dev/posts/2025-12-23-printing-non-null-terminated-strings-with-gdb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In C, a string is an array of characters terminated by the null terminator character &lt;code&gt;&#39;\0&#39;&lt;/code&gt; (ASCII 0x0). String handling functions like &lt;code&gt;strlen&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;strcpy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;strcmp&lt;/code&gt;, etc. use the null terminator to determine where the string data ends. Without it, string handling functions can read past the intended memory, leading to undefined behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in gdb, when printing a string or examining a memory address as a string (using &lt;code&gt;x/s &amp;lt;addr&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;), both the printf and examine commands also rely on the null terminator to determine where a string ends. However, sometimes programs store strings without a null terminator, and their functions use a length parameter instead to indicate the length of a string.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item><item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://www.0xChris.dev/posts/2025-12-18-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.0xChris.dev/posts/2025-12-18-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! This is the very first post, and I’m excited to start sharing my thoughts, ideas, and projects with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be writing about things I&amp;rsquo;m interested in and topics I’m passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not much to see here yet, but ideas are taking shape and drafts are in the works — stay tuned and thanks for stopping by!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item></channel>
</rss>